以下影片描述《超人第二部》
当初构思及筹画开拍的过程
有些片段来自画面测试中 我们无法拍摄的桥段
这部电影是用以纪念 克里斯多夫李维
没有他 我们绝不会相信人类能飞
我要求你们念出
I ask you now to pronounce judgment…
判决的内容
…on those accused.
对这些被告
On this…
对这个无情的叛离者 他只想以暴力和破坏
This mindless aberration, whose only means of expression…
来表现其情感
…are wanton violence and destruction.
对这个女人亚莎…
On the woman, Ursa…
她对所有全体人类的 曲解及不合理的仇恨心态
…whose perversionsand unreasoning hatred of all mankind…
已经威胁到 全体氪星的儿童
…have threatened even the childrenof the planet Krypton.
最后一位是查德将军
Finally, General Zod.
创造者希望对这种预谋
Chief architect of this intended revolution…
重新建立一项秩序所作之革命 加以摧毁
…and author of this insidious plotto establish a new order amongst us…
好让自己仍然成为 绝对之统治者
…with himself as absolute ruler.
现在宣布判决的结果
The decision of the council will now be heard.
有罪
Guilty.
- 有罪 - 有罪
- Guilty. - Guilty.
有罪
Guilty.
本项表决具有敌意 乔艾尔
The vote must be unanimous, Jor-El.
现在已经变成你的判决
It has therefore now become your decision.
如果你希望的话 你就判我们有罪吧
You alone will condemn us if you wish…
那你此要对我这件事负责了
…and you alonewill be held responsible by me.
你会在我面前屈服的 乔艾尔
You will bow down before me, Jor-El.
我发誓
I swear it.
不管天长地久 你终会在我面前屈服的
No matter that it takes an eternity, you will bow down before me!
你们两个
Both you…
将来…
…and then one day…
还有你的子孙
…your heirs!
你会在我面前屈服的
You will bow down before me!
- 原谅我 - 我会回来的
- Forgive me! - I'll be back!
原谅我
Forgive me!
你母亲诺拉寄给你 红 黄 蓝 三条毯子
Your mother Lara has sent youthree blankets, of red, yellow and blue.
它们能保护你 确保你的力量
Their protectionwill ensure your strength.
是氪石 超人 从古老家乡来的纪念品
It's kryptonite, Superman.A little souvenir from the old hometown.
你是很厉害 超人 不过应该是…
You were great in your day, Superman.But it just stands to reason…
要收拾你的时候了
…when it came timeto cash in your chips…
这位老而有病的疯子
…this old, diseased maniac…
将成为你的主宰
…would be your banker.
小心肌肉过度紧绷
Mind over muscle.
你为何先吻我？
Why did you kiss me first?
我觉得你待会儿不会让我吻你
It… I didn't think you'd let me later.
站一边去
Stand aside, now.
自由了
Free!
《超人2》
新群哈密瓜 非常新鲜的哈密瓜 要买新鲜就在这里
Nice fresh melons.Nice fresh melons. Get them fresh here.
用来烹饪也很好喔 你看看 最好的
Good for the cooking, huh?Look at this, the best.
「雷克斯路瑟的炸弹阴谋 超人拯救国家
"Lex Luthor's scheme bombs.Superman saves nation.
犯罪之王被判重刑 露易丝莲恩独家报导
Master criminal draws harsh sentence.Exclusive story by Lois Lane.
吉姆欧森摄影「
Photographs by James Olsen."
雷克斯路瑟 你看起来永远这么邪恶
Luthor, you never looked lovelier.
露易丝 做得好
Lois, terrific job.
- 谢了 老编 - 非常好的报导 非常好
- Thanks, chief. - Great story, really great.
早安 老编 你迟到了
Hey, good morning, chief. You're late.
莲恩小姐 这故事很棒 是最棒的之一
Yeah, Miss Lane, that's a great story.One of the best.
吉姆 通常一张照片 不值得我写一千字
Well, Jimmy, usually a picture isn't worth a thousand words when I write the story…
但以这则报导来说 恭喜你
…but in this case, congratulations.
- 多谢了 - 是啊
- Yeah, thanks a lot. - Yeah.
肯特先生来了 我赌他希望 事件发生时他能在场
There's Mr. Kent. Bet he wisheshe'd been around when it all happened.
超人出现时克拉克都不在场
Clark, he's never around when Superman appears.
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
（揭开超人的秘密）
- 头版还有位置吗？ - 有
- You got a page in the front? - Yeah.
莲恩小姐有绝对正点的报导
Miss Lane got the best story.
早安 露易丝
Good morning, Lois.
嗨
Hi.
莲恩 肯特 进来
Lane, Kent, get in here!
看吧 吉姆 你害我有麻烦了
Now, see, Jimmy, you got me in trouble.
- 我们刚刚正在谈话 - 再见 是个天大的错误
- We were talking. - So long. A big mistake.
下一次别这样对我
Next time, don't do that to me.
- 早安 露易丝 你今天好吗？ - 非常好 谢谢
- Good morning, Lois. How are you today? - Oh, I'm just super. Thanks.
- 早安 白先生 - 我很好
- Good morning, Mr. White. - I'm super.
- 早安 你迟到了 肯特 - 我知道 很抱歉 白先生
- Yeah, morning. You're late, Kent. - I know. I'm sorry, Mr. White.
- 路上塞车 - 又有新借口了
- I got stuck in traffic. - Oh, that's a new one.
- 你说什么？ - 我是说
- Excuse me? - I mean, as opposed to:
除了「我被卡在电话亭里」或「我被锁在男厕里」之外
"I was stuck in a phone booth" or"I got locked into the men's bathroom."
露易丝 你在说什么？ 我很抱歉我迟到了
Lois, what are you talking about?I'm sorry I was late.
你们想吵闹的话 我刚好有任务给你们
If you two wanna bicker, I have just the assignment for you.
你们要扮成蜜月小夫妻 参加一个新婚宴会
You're gonna pose as a honeymoon coupleto get an expos?on the newlywed racket.
有些饭店压榨这些可怜孩子的微薄收入
Some of those hotels are bilkingthose poor kids for every cent they can get.
是条令人成兴趣的新闻 保证那些婆婆妈妈痛哭流涕
Real human-interest stuff.Make your Aunt Hattie cry her eyes out.
- 新婚夫妇？ - 这主意真棒 白先生
- Newlyweds? - That is a great idea, Mr. White.
对不起 但我正在追踪一系列…
I'm sorry, but I'm in the middle of a series…
那不会花上你很多时间
I mean, it wouldn't take long.
我们可以直接飞过去 再飞回来
We could just fly right up thereand zoom back down again.
不好吗 超人？
No, Superman?
对 要是他愿意载你们一程 也许我们能省下一些钱
Yeah. If he'd give you two a ride, maybe we could save a couple bucks.
我要找小欧森 六张龌龊的照片…
I gotta see young Olsen.Six lousy photographs…
那小子还一直吵加薪
…and that kid's hitting me up for a raise.
抱歉 白先生 我们能谈谈吗？
Excuse me. Mr. White? Could we talk?
可恶
Darn.
你看起来像吞了一只金丝雀的猫
You look like the cat who swallowedthe canary this morning.
金丝雀？才不 是更大的东西
A canary? No, actually I wasthinking of something bigger…
一种会飞的 颜色更蓝的东西
…something that flies, something more in blue.
露易丝 我和以往一样 身陷黑暗中…
Lois, as usual, I'm totally in the dark…
让我为你把灯点亮
Let me just turn on the lights for you then.
懂了吗？
Get the picture?
我到现在才拼凑出全貌 真的蛮有趣的
I didn't put this together untilthis morning. Which is really strange…
因为一名记者 绝不会忽略任何细节
…because a good reporter isn't supposed to let anything slip by her.
那很有趣 没错
Well, that's very amusing. Yes.
- 不好意思 - 有趣？
- Excuse me. - Amusing?
- 是的 非常有趣 - 有趣是吧？
- Yes, sirree, that's… That's very amusing. - Amusing, huh?
高大 宽阔的肩膀
Tall, broad shoulders…
深色头发
…dark hair.
我得承认你伪装的很成功
Gotta give you credit, you really had me fooled.
我没有骗任何人
And I'm nobody's fool…
超人
…Superman.
超人？
Superman?
你是说你以为我是超人？
You mean you think I'm Superman?
我愿意用生命作赌注
Willing to bet my life on it.
露易丝 你知道吗？你是无价的
Lois, you know, you are priceless.
真的 那是我知道最可笑的事了
Really. That is the single mostridiculous thing I've ever…
- 露易丝 你在做什么？ - 你不会让我死的 超人
- Lois, what are you doing? - You wouldn't let me die, Superman.
- 老天 - 救她出来 救她出来
- Oh, God. - Help her out. Help her out.
- 克拉克 - 露易丝 你做了什么？
- Clark! - Lois, what have you done?
克拉克 你不是…
Clark, the… You're not…
克拉克 你有见到露易丝吗？
Hey, Clark, you seen Lois?
她刚刚出去了
She just stepped out for a minute.
这是本世代最伟大罪犯的下场
This is how it ends forthe greatest criminal mind of our time.
没有人哭也没有人闹
Not with a whimper, not with a bang.
他们将如何纪念雷克斯路瑟
How do they choose to reward Lex Luthor…
这位世上最伟大的天才？
…the greatest genius in this world?
他们给他荣耀还是宝藏？ 说实话 他们给了什么？
Do they give him glory or treasure?What, matter of fact, do they give him?
终生监禁外加廿五年 快工作
Life plus 25, Luthor. Get to work.
别伤心 路瑟先生 你差点就成功了
Don't feel bad, Mr. Luthor.It almost worked.
我说的是加州差点就沉入海底
I mean, California almost fell down, right in the ocean.
百万人几乎丧命
Millions of people was almost killed.
如果不是超人 那个成长过度的男童军
If it hadn't been for that guy Superman, that overgrown Boy Scout.
- 今晚我将要回我的自由 - 今晚？
- I want my Liberace record back tonight. - Tonight?
那种人你要怎么对付？ 他飞那么快又什么都会
What are you gonna do with a guy like that?He flies around so fast and everything.
甚至连雷达都无法追踪
I mean, they can't even tracethat guy on that radar they got.
只要他们想追踪 他马上飞走
Every time they try, he just flies off.
- 往哪个方向？ - 北方
- Where? - North.
为什么？
Why?
为了去滑雪？
To ski?
欧提斯 每个人都有弱点
Otis, every man has his vulnerable point.
像你这种人的弱点不止一个
Some, like you, Otis, have more than one.
我没能及时看到超人
I didn't see Superman's in time.
现在通过耐心 创造力及技术
But now, through patience, invention, and skill…
我的小黑箱就快完成了
…my little black boxis just about ready.
我们囚房中的小黑箱
Oh, that little black box in our cell?
那个小黑箱 路瑟先生
That little black box, Mr. Luthor…
那有什么用途？
…what's it for?
那个小黑箱比传统雷达有用
That little black box goes beyond any normal, conventional radar.
它能追踪阿尔法波
It tracks alpha waves.
阿尔法波
Alpha waves. Yeah.
我可以说这模仿青豆面条 是吧？
I could've said it tracked pasta e fagioli, couldn't I?
要加上大蒜和奶油 路瑟先生
Oh, with garlic, Mr. Luthor. And butter.
老天
Boy.
阿尔法波能引我到北极 到他的秘密
Those alpha waves willtake me north to his secret.
当我知道超人的秘密 我就不怕他了
And when I have his secret, I'll have Superman.
屠杀者佛吉斯顿是个尿床小鬼
Slasher Fogelstein's a bed wetter.
屠杀者佛吉斯顿是个尿床小鬼 传下去
Slasher Fogelstein's a bed wetter.Pass it.
你好 佛吉斯顿先生
Hi, Mr. Fogelstein.
太快了 你能用正常速度吗？
too fast. Can you get the speed right?
我告诉你 他们三周前就装好了
I told you, they installed thosethree weeks ago.
嗨
Hey.
你来监视一下这跳动符号 它让我头很痛
You follow the bouncing ball for a while.Thing's giving me a headache.
总之 派人去查看那些家伙
Anyway, somebody's gotta check up on those guys.
说得对 我老是把他们忘了
Yeah, I keep on forgetting about them.
他们在上面多久了？45天？
How long they been up there, 45 days?
全世界都已将我们遗忘了
The whole world's forgotten about it.
休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝二号
Houston calling Artemis II.
休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝二号 请回答
Houston calling Artemis II. Come in.
- 早安 休士顿 - 等一下 纳特
- Morning, Houston. - Hold on, Nate.
- 喂 - 情况如何？
- Yo. - How are things going?
一切系统都很正常 休士顿
All systems normal, Houston.
安迪正在外面进行地质调查
Andy is out doing the geological survey.
更多石头
More rocks. Nice.
柯斯墨诺伯里斯正在采土样
And cosmonaut Borisis getting some soil samples.
对了 伯里斯跟我订婚了
By the way, Boris and I are engaged.
当我看到你的罗夏墨渍测验时 心中已经有数
I had a feeling about you guyswhen I saw your Rorschach tests.
只是闲玩笑舒缓一下 休士顿
Just a little detente humor there, Houston.
表面状况没有改变吗？
Surface conditions unchanged?
外太空的景色非常美丽
Well, it's mightypretty out there. Mighty…
- 非常美丽… - 没错
- …pretty. - Mighty pretty.
对
Right.
听我说 纳特…
Look, Nate?
纳特 专心点好吗？
Nate, wake up, will you?
没错 我是在作梦
That's it. I'm dreaming.
阿特蜜丝 请回答
Artemis, come in.
休士顿 这里好像出现不明飞行物
Well, Houston, we seem to havean unidentified flying object.
不明飞行物？
Unidentified?
- 它是什么样子？ - 很像是…
- What does it look like? - Well…
一个女孩
…a lot like a girl.
你
You.
- 你是何种生物？ - 我是个男人
- What kind of a creature are you? - Just a man.
你是男人？
A man?
真脆弱的生命
What a fragile sort of life form this is.
休士顿 请回答 休士顿
Houston, come in. Come in, Houston.
请回答 休士顿 请回答
Come in, Houston. Come in.
尝试手动起飞
Attempting manual liftoff.
有人听到我吗？
Can somebody hear me?
休士顿
Houston!
快啊
Come on.
快点啊 休士顿
Come on, Houston!
喔 不…
Oh, no. No!
谁来救我
Somebody help me!
- 休士顿呼叫阿特蜜丝 请回答 - 怎么回事？
- Artemis, Houston calling. Come in. - What's going on?
- 我不知道 我们失去连系了 - 所以呢？
- I don't know. We've lost contact. - So?
我说的是真的
Well, we really…
阿特蜜丝 请回答
Artemis, come in, please.
好了 你们谁在用吹风机？
All right, which one of you guysis using the hair dryer?
好奇怪 那些金属我撕起来像在撕纸
Strange. I tore those metal fibers like paper.
而他的举动 真是太惊人了…
And what he did was amazing.
- 有些改变发生了 - 没错 我们三个都一样
- Something is happening. - Yes, to all of us.
我们愈接近 只有一个太阳的大气层
The closer we come to anatmosphere with only one sun…
一个黄色的太阳…
…a yellow sun…
我们的分子密度愈大 也给予我们无穷的力量
…the more our moleculardensity gives us unlimited powers.
他们来自那里
They come from there.
一个叫做休士顿的地方
A place called Houston.
那么我们也去那里
Then we will go there too…
去统治那个星球
…to rule.
终于…能够统治星球了
Finally, to rule.
382室 熄灯
Three-eighty-two, out.
383室 熄灯
Three-eighty-three, out.
384室 熄灯
Three-eighty-four, out.
385室 熄灯
Three-eighty-five, out.
熄灯 路瑟
Lights out, Luthor.
我叫你熄灯
I said, lights out.
再十秒我就会进去找你们 听到了没有？
You guys are about 10 seconds away from solitary, you know that?
我叫你们…
I told you to…
不要动 不要动
Freeze, freeze.
路瑟先生
Mr. Luthor.
- 我们要怎么越过那道墙？ - 我们怎么进来的？
- How we gonna get over that wall? - How'd we get in?
- 我们飞进来的 记得吗？ - 那我们就飞出去
- We flew in here, remember? - That's how we'll get out.
不 不是那家伙
Oh, no, not that guy.
你刚刚叫我吗？
Did you just go "psst"?
我希望我有 路瑟先生 在我们离开前
I wish I had, Mr. Luthor, before we left.
不是那个 是那个
Not that "psst, " that "psst."
- 当我这样时别那样 - 你去做
- Don't go "psst" when I go "psst." - You do it.
快出去找一找
Go out there and find it.
- 我要找什么？ - 你看到时说会知道
- What am I looking for? - You'll know when you see it.
我想我找到了
I think I found it.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是个楼梯 傻瓜
It's a ladder, you dummy.
黛丝玛克小姐 你好
Hi, Miss Teschmacher.
来
Come on.
动作快
Hurry up. Hurry up.
快一点
Come on, hurry.
欧提斯 抓住楼梯 快点
Otis, hold that ladder. Hurry up.
码线 达阵 喔 打得真是太好了
yard line, touchdown!Oh, what a beautiful play.
不过裁判丢了手帕 它可能是某队犯规…
But there's a marker down field.It could be against…
- 上来啊 - 快点
- Come up. - Come on.
我来了 路瑟先生
Here I come, Mr. Luthor.
- 下去 下去 - 欧提斯
- Get off. Get off. - Otis!
- 欧提斯 我们在往下掉 - 下去 快下去
- We're sinking! - Get off, get off!
黛丝玛克小姐 你做得很好
Very good, Miss Teschmacher. Very good.
- 我来这里干嘛？我为什么在这里？ - 黛丝玛克小姐…
- What am I doing here? Why am I here? - Miss Teschmacher…
这是哲学课吗？
…is this a philosophy seminar?
不 这是通道
No. This is a getaway.
- 通道？ - 没错
- Getaway. - Right.
这很天才 我不知道你哪儿来的灵感
It's ingenious. I don't know where you got the inspiration from.
从你那里得来的 雷克斯
I got it from you, Lex.
热气上升
Hot air rises.
你想来赵旅行吗？
Would you like to take a trip?
旅行？放大假吗？
A trip? A vacation.
雷克斯 我可以去血拼 买件比基尼
Lex, I can go shopping.I can buy a bikini.
你想要我在监狱里穿着比基尼？
You thought about me in a bikiniwhile in prison?
不 我其实没那么想
No, I didn't, actually.
我想的你是穿着毛皮外套
I thought about you in a parka.
我穿毛皮外套？
You thought about me in a parka?
你很病态 雷克斯 你真的病了
You are sick, Lex. You are really sick.
有可能
That's possible.
往北 黛丝玛克小姐
North, Miss Teschmacher.
正北方
Due north.
雷克斯 北方
Lex, north.
就像我所说的 正北方
That's what I said, due north.
- 你的确说过 - 我知道我说我说过了
- That's what you said. - I know I said I said that.
- 我刚刚才听到 - 对 雷克斯
- I just heard it. - Yes, Lex.
别重复我说的话
Don't repeat what I say when I say something.
- 我不会重复你说的话 - 好 别重复就是
- I won't repeat what you say. - Okay, don't.
别再重复我的话
Well, stop repeating me.
（蜜月天堂饭店）
对不起
Excuse me.
你是否想抱着史密斯太太 进入门槛…
Would you like to carry Mrs. Smith over the threshold?
那是一种传统
It's sort of traditional.
如果你抱不动 我可以帮忙
I can give you a handif you have trouble lifting.
- 不用了 当然不用 - 亲爱的 谢谢 我自己走
- No, of course not. - Honey. Thanks, I'll walk.
没问题 亲爱的
Certainly, dear.
快跑 快跑
Mush! Mush!
我已经在跑了
I am mushing.
往北 黛丝玛克小姐
North, Miss Teschmacher.
- 往北 往北 - 是的 雷克斯 往北
- North, north! - Yes, Lex. North.
你一定弄错了 雷克斯 这种地方 一定不是他的家
Oh, you must be wrong, Lex.This couldn't be his home way up here.
「你错了 雷克斯」
"Wrong, Lex."
黛丝玛克小姐 不能出现在同 那两个词 个句子里
Miss Teschmacher, those are two words we do not use in the same sentence.
这很古怪 它没有大门
Well, it's funny there's no front door.
「古怪」 黛丝玛克小姐 是指有人笑不露齿
Miss Teschmacher, "funny" is a person trying to smile without any teeth.
是的
Right.
好了 过来 雷克斯 过来
All right, come on, Lex. Come on.
让开
Move out of the way.
- 这边 - 是这边
- This way. - It's this way.
雷克斯 是这边
Lex, it's this way.
是这边 雷克斯
It's this way, Lex.
- 来吧 来啊 - 别碰我
- Come on. Come on. - Get off!
来吧
Come on.
- 太好了 - 太好了
- Fantastic. - Fantastic.
真是好极了
It's fantastic!
目前所知的建筑理论 都无法完成这栋建筑物
The construction goes far beyondany known architectural theory.
- 真的是很美 - 很美
- It's beautiful. - It's beautiful.
- 雷克斯 - 我没事的
- Lex. - I'll be all right.
不 是我
No, me.
你为什么不能更小心一点？
Why can't you be more careful?
- 真的是很美 - 很美
- It's beautiful. - Beautiful.
- 这里什么都有 - 错了
- It has everything. - Wrong.
- 我们出发前 你为何不去上？ - 那是两天前的事了
- Why didn't you go before we left? - That was two days ago.
小心点 雷克斯
Be careful, Lex.
别碰…
Get!
坦白说我觉得这地方有点无聊 到处一片洁白
Frankly, I think this placeis a little boring. It's all white.
这家伙赶麻不放些照片上去？
Why doesn't the guy put up some pictures?
或许可以放些斗牛海报
Maybe some bullfighting posters.
- 什么都别碰 - 什么都别碰
- Don't touch anything. - Don't touch anything.
- 是冰 - 我说过别碰它
- Ice. - I said, don't touch it.
- 这不是冰 - 看起来像是水晶
- It's not ice. - It looks like a crystal.
正直的灵魂 不需要别人的感谢…
The virtuous spirit has no need for thankful approval…
- 搞什么？ - 来获得一些肯定…
- What the… - Owning a certain conviction…
确定自己做的那件事是对的
…that what has been done is right.
这就是他老爸 他看起来跟超人很像
That's the old man.He looks just like the kid.
- 你就是老爸吗？ - 问他厕所在哪里？
- Are you the old man? - Ask him where the bathroom is.
你必须靠自己来肯定
Develop such conviction in yourself.
你在吗？
Are you here?
- 在你的星球上的人心 - 他不在这里
- The human heart on your planet… - He's not here.
这声音来自过去 真聪明
It's a voice from the past.That's cute. That's really cute. Nice.
谎言 骇人听闻的诡计
Lies, monstrous deceptions.
真会说教
So much for moral rearmament.
给我另一块水晶
Give me another crystal.
第108号教育水晶 地球文化
Education crystal 108. Earth culture.
这是地球人们 相当喜爱的一首词赋 凯尔
A typical ode much loved by the people you will live among, Kal-El.
乔尹斯基尔默讲述「树」
Trees by Joyce Kilmer.
「我认为我永远不会看到
"I think that I shall never see
一首如树木般美丽的诗「
A poem as lovely as a tree."
别这样 我喜欢树木
Come on, I like trees.
你那只柯卡猎犬也一样 再给我另外一个
So does your average cocker spaniel.Give me another.
真好笑
Cute.
我的儿子…
My son…
- 他长生不老 - 长生不老
- The man never ages. - Never ages.
是该告诉你我们星球历史中 的黑暗时期了
…the time has come to tell you of the darkest episode in Krypton history.
- 这才是我想听的 - 很不幸地…
- Now, this I wanna hear. - Unfortunately…
即使在我们平静的星球上
…even on our peaceful planet…
一些扰乱世界的元素
…there have appearedonce in a great while…
依旧每隔一阵子出现一次
…certain antisocial elements.
异常者
Deviants…
也就是地球上所说的罪犯
…what you call on Earth "criminals."
罪犯？
Criminals.
异常者 他一开始就说对了
Deviants. He was right in the first place.
虽然我们不像地球一样 是个苦难的星球
Though of course, we are nota penalty planet like Earth…
这些不快乐的灵魂 几乎全数成功转换为…
…and these unhappy souls were almostalways successfully transformed…
- 奉公守法的市民 - 你没听过雷克斯路瑟吗？
- …into productive citizens. - You never heard of Lex Luthor?
只有三者例外 只有这三者
There were, however, three exceptions… Only three.
证明了自己不可能脱离邪恶
who proved impossible to rehabilitate.
还有希望
There's hope.
零 是毁灭者
Non, the destroyer.
以人类的形体进行无理由的暴力
Unreasoning violence in the shape of a being.
亚莎 邪恶又残忍
Ursa. Vicious, cruel, obsessed by a single-minded hatred…
一心被无法确定的仇恨驱使
…which could never be determined.
还有一股汇集他们的力量
And the one force that could unite them…
唯一能以他异常的聪颖 驾驭邪恶力量的人
…the only one whose warped genius could harness these forces of evil:
查德将军
General Zod.
- 他看起来满可爱的 - 他意图叛乱
- He looks kind of cute. - His intended insurrection…
那是我们人民最痛苦的一段历史
…was the most painful episode our people ever had to endure.
在漫长恐怖的一役后
But after a long and terrible battle…
星球再次恢复和平与和谐
…peace and harmony were once again restored.
满令人扫兴的结局
Kind of an anticlimax.
我们并没有死刑
We had, of course, no death penalty.
非常合理
Sensible enough.
他们因而被封印在幽灵区
And so they were placed in the Phantom Zone…
永远监禁他们
…to be imprisoned for all eternity.
我们并不知道 若让他们逃走会有什么后果
I do not know what could be done if they were to escape.
在氪星 无法控制这些恶徒
On Krypton, thesevillains were uncontrollable.
在地球上 他们每个人 都可能拥有强大的力量
On Earth, each of them would have the identical powers…
跟你的力量完全一样
…that you have.
想想看 有三名超级恶徒
Think of it. Three super villains.
每个人的力量都跟他一样
All three with the same power he has.
每一位都具都有毁坏 暴力及邪恶倾向
All three totally dedicated to corruption, violence, evil.
他们需要一位地球联络人
They need a contact on Earth.
和他们拥有同样感受的人
Someone who felt the same as they did, someone who…
某位与他们同样争取生命自由 并追求快乐的人
…had the same wonderful contempt for life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.
一位好的不可思议的人
Too true to be good.
对吗？
Right?
- 黛丝玛克小姐？ - 我找到了
- Miss Teschmacher? - I found it.
我想是
I think.
- 我需要吉姆时 他在哪里？ - 风景真美 不是吗？
- Where's Jimmy Olsen when I need him? - Golly, isn't it beautiful?
太美了 美极了
Yeah, it's gorgeous. Gorgeous.
- 露易丝 - 什么事？
- Lois? - Yeah?
你看 每个人都牵着手 或许我们也该牵手？
Look. Everybody's holding hands.Maybe we should hold hands too, huh?
- 克拉克 牵着我的手吧 - 谢谢
- Here's my hand, Clark. Hold it. - Thanks.
你知道吗？他们都不敢放手
You know what? They're afraid to let go.
- 为什么？ - 因为他们一放手就会离婚
- Why? - They let go, straight to the lawyer.
这点我并不清楚 我觉得他们看来都很快乐
Oh, I don't know about that.They look kind of happy to me.
因为你视而不见 克拉克
That's because you're blind, Clark.
- 是吧 - 过来
- Oh, yeah. - Here.
- 不用了 我戴着就行 - 克拉克
- No, I've got it. No, I… - Yeah. Clark.
你得好好照顾自己 你只有一双眼睛
You've gotta look after yourself.You've only got one pair of eyes.
- 天啊 - 露易丝
- God. - Lois?
- 拿去 - 是的
- Now, here. - Right.
- 别说我什么都没做… - 谢谢
- Don't say I never did anything for you. - Thank you.
小子 对不起
Son! Excuse me, please.
- 小心点 - 你在干什么？
- Be careful. - What are you doing?
下来 快下来
Get down! Get down!
你在众人面前害我丢脸
You embarrass me here in front of everybody.
你看到差点出事了吗？ 那个小男孩…
Lois, did you see what almost happened there? That little boy…
我饿了 你饿了吗？
Hey, I'm hungry. You hungry?
- 露易丝 你真是不可思议 - 因为我肚子饿？
- Lois, you're amazing. - Why, because I'm hungry?
不是 站在自然界中 最壮观的景色之前…
No. Here you are standing in front of one of nature's most awesome spectacles…
而你只想到要吃东西 难道你不为美景所震撼？
…and you're thinking about food. Aren't you impressed?
克拉克 当女孩子看过行动中的超人后
Clark, once a girl's seen Superman in action…
尼亚加拉瀑布只会让你觉得冷 你了解我的意思吗？
…Niagara Falls kind of leaves you cold, you know?
又是他
Him again, huh?
对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我的心胸很狭窄的吧
I have a one-track mind, don't I?
我狭窄的心胸告诉我 我饿了
Well, my one-track mind is telling me that I'm hungry.
- 吃热狗好吗？ - 吃热狗
- Hot dog? - Hot dog.
热狗
Hot dog.
我还要柳橙汁
Could I have some orange juice?
- 现榨的 - 现榨的 我知道
- Freshly squeezed. - Freshly squeezed, I know.
嘿 妈 你看
Hey, Mom. Look!
亲爱的 你很棒
Yeah, honey. That's nice.
好 我要两个加芥末和碎酸黄瓜的 还有…
Okay, it's two mustard and relish, and…
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
救命
Help!
快来人帮帮忙
Somebody help!
快帮忙啊
Do something!
很好
Good.
超人
Hey, Superman!
干得好 超人
Way to go, Superman!
我们拍到一个好镜头
We got a great shot.
真是个大好人
What a nice man.Of course he's Jewish.
真不可思议
Incredible.
（迷雾之女四号）
- 你到了 - 再飞一次 再飞一次
- There you go. - Again, again!
对不起 每个人只能飞一次
No, I'm sorry.Only one ride to a customer.
- 超人 超人 是我 露易丝 - 再见
- Superman. Superman, it's me, it's Lois! - Bye.
过来 我要好好修理你
Come here. You're gonna get it!
- 你害我差点心脏病发作 - 是我 露易丝
- Give me a heart attack here. - It's me. It's Lois.
是露易丝·莲啊
It's Lois Lane.
你好 再见
Well, hello and goodbye.
这就是休士顿星吗？
So this is planet Houston.
好奇怪的地表
A very strange surface.
- 我的天啊 - 没关系
- Oh, my gosh. - Oh, that's all right.
- 我只是没听见你敲门 此这样 - 露易丝
- I just didn't hear you knock, that's all. - Lois…
门根本没锁 任何人都进得来
…the door wasn't even locked.Just anybody can walk in here.
- 你又把自己比喻为凡人了 - 很幽默
- There you go putting yourself down again. - Very funny.
不 我很认真
No, really, I'm serious.
无论如何…
Well, anyway…
这是给今晚新婚晚宴的一点小东西
…here, a little something forthe newlyweds' dinner tonight.
是紫罗兰 克拉克 这很… 很特别
Pansies. Clark, how…How different.
你相信它们在这儿 都是野生的吗？
Would you believethey grow wild all around here?
你应该看看花店里玫瑰的价格
You should see what they charge for roses at the gift shop.
我想也是
I'll bet, huh?
- 你知道吗 露易丝？ - 什么？
- You know something, Lois? - What?
除了这件事的不真实以外…
Well, you know, in spite of the unreality of all this…
你知道的 为了报导装扮成新婚夫妻
Well, you know, posing as newlyweds for the sake of a newspaper story.
除了我自己甚至都…
Well, in spite of myself even…
我闻始觉得自己是其中之一了
…I'm kind of starting to feel like one in a way.
- 新婚夫妻 你？ - 我不觉得那有什么好奇怪
- A newlywed, you? - I don't see why that should be so strange.
抱歉 我不是那个意思
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
我是说 我确定有成千上万的女孩愿意…
I mean, I'm sure there's thousands of girls who'd…
至少有几个
Well, a few girls anyway.
- 尽管说出来 - 说什么？
- Go ahead and say it. - Say what?
说你不满意和我一起待在这里
That somehow you're not satisfied being here with me.
我在你眼里看来不太完美
That in some way I don't seem to shape up very well in your eyes.
我无需为任何事道歉 我是个好记者
I don't have anything to apologize for.I'm a good reporter.
不 我是个非常好的记者 还是你更好的朋友
No, I'm a very good reporter.And an even better friend to you.
- 站起来 - 站起来？
- Stand up. - Stand up?
对 站起来 好玩嘛
Yeah, stand up, just for fun.
过来这里 看看你自己 看看你自己
Now, come here. Look at yourself.Just look at yourself.
这是个有潜在攻击性 与威胁性的男人
What we have here is a potentially aggressive, dynamite guy…
他能呼风唤雨
…who can do anything he wants.
这不是我的错 你一直自贬身价
I mean, it's not my fault you keep putting yourself down.
- 是吗？怎么说？ - 首先
- Oh, yeah? How? - Well, for starters…
你装作一副笨拙的样子 来 站直
…you slouch all the time.Here, stand up straight.
这样好多了
There, that's better.
替自己买件有开口的夹克 和不用带子束紧的鞋
And get yourself a jacket with a vent and shoes that don't lace up…
和一件有点颜色 或图形之类的衬衫
…and a shirt with a little color or a pattern or something.
和一个看起来不像拆信刀的领结
And a bow tie that doesn't look like a letter opener.
好吧 露慧丝 好吧
All right, Lois. All right.
- 我们讨论过这个了不是？ - 是的
- We've been through this, haven't we? - Yes.
我知道这一切的结局
I know where this is all leading to.
我很抱歉 我很抱歉…
And I'm sorry. I mean, I'm sorry…
不论我多努力尝试 我就是…
…but no matter how hard I try, I just…
就是永远不会变成他
Just… Just never will be him.
他是谁？
Him who?
「他是谁」 ？当然是超人
"Him who"? Him Superman.
你似乎以为自己爱他 我无力改变这点
Now, I can't help the fact thatyou seem to think that you love him.
这是我要忍受的地方 可恶 露易丝 我受够了
That's something I'll have to live with.But darn it, Lois, that's enough now.
或许我受够和他较劲了
Maybe I just can't stand the competition anymore.
也许你一直以来就是那个对手？
And just maybe you've been the competition all along.
露易丝 我从不擅长猜谜
Lois, I've never been particularly good at riddles.
让我把话说白一点
Let me make this one really easy for you.
全世界有无数孩子可能身陷危险
Why, with thousands of children potentially falling off something lethal…
为什么超人今天会在尼加拉瀑布？
…all around the world, would Superman be in Niagara Falls today?
为什么不是大峡谷？
Why not the Grand Canyon?
问问孩子的家人 他们知道答案
Ask the child's family. I'm sure they know.
为何每次都是我和你在一起…
Why is it always when I'm with you…
直到超人现身？ 然复你似乎就消失了
…until Superman appears?And then you seem to disappear.
- 我一直觉得这巧合并不单纯 - 天啊 我是去买热狗
- Very conveniently, it seems to me. - I was out for hot dogs. For Pete's sake…
当超人来到现场时 我转头看热狗摊
When Superman appeared, I looked at that hot dog stand…
你已经不在了
…and you were gone.
- 我是… - 消失无踪
- I was… - Nowhere.
我非去不可也没办法…
I can't help it if I had to go to the…
你就是超人 对吧？
You are Superman, aren't you?
露易丝 我们以前就谈过 你的这种幻觉
Lois, look, we've been through these hallucinations of yours before.
你知道你差点做了什么事吗？
Can't you see what you almost did?
从30楼高跳下？
Throwing yourself off a building 30 stories high?
你知道那差点 铸成不幸的错误吗？
Can't you see the tragic mistake you almost made?
对 我的确是犯了错 因为…
Yeah, I made a mistake.I made a mistake because…
我用的生命冒险 而不是你的
…I risked my life instead of yours.
露易丝 别这样
Lois, don't be insane.
别想假装倒下去 因为你还得站起来
And don't fall down because you're just gonna have to get up again.
露易丝 别闹了 露易丝
Lois, now, don't be crazy now. Lois!
就是你
It is you.
我想我一定知道很久了
I guess I've known this for the longest time.
你一定很清楚
You realize, of course…
若猜错的话 克拉克肯特就死了
…if you'd been wrong, Clark Kent would have been killed.
用空包弹也会死吗？
With a blank?
骗到你了吧
Gotcha.
多么原始的生命啊
A primitive sort of life form.
你看到了吗？
Did you see that?
Did you see what I did?
我拥有超凡的力量
I have powers beyond reason here.
我们三个都有 亲爱的
We all have them, my dear.
- 这里就是你家 - 不是
- Wow, this is your home? - No.
事实上我住在城里 离你家三条街而已
Actually, I live in the city, about three blocks from you.
这里对我是个很特殊的地方
No, this is a very special place for me.
我想让你看看这里
I wanted you to see it.
你感觉够暖和吗？
Listen, you warm enough?
我应该觉得冷 但我并不冷
I guess I should be freezing, but I'm not.
很好
Good.
来吧 我带你四处看看
Come on, let me show you.
不知道耶
I don't know.
从他们的外表看来 十元赌他们来自洛杉矶
From the look of them, I'll bet $10 they're from Los Angeles.
痞子 别档路
Hey, you hippies, get your butts off the road!
我喜欢那颗闪亮的红灯 就如同氪星的太阳
I like the globe. It flashes red like our Krypton sun.
但不喜欢那恼人的噪音
But not this irritating noise.
让开
Make way.
我听对了吗？
Did I hear right?
那个混球对我下命令？
That son of a bitch give me an order?
杜安 让你来处理
Duane, you take care of it.
（郡立警长）
好吧 你以为你在做什么？
Just what in the hell do you think you're doing here?
这是什么标志？
What is this symbol?
你追随其他颌导人吗？
Do you follow another leader?
追随领导人？
Follow the leader?
痛死了
Holy skunk sweat.
- 好吧… - 这是什么武器？
- All right. - A weapon of some sort.
你怎么办到的？
How the hell did you do that?
我的老天爷啊
Jesus H. Christ.
- 那样很好 - 我想或许我们…
- That was good. - I thought we might…
这次能够省咯橘子汁
…abandon the orange juice for once.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Here, cheers. - Cheers.
扮演克拉克肯特很辛苦吧？
Must be tough being Clark Kent, isn't it?
不会
No. No, I really…
有时我还蛮喜欢的
I really like it sometimes.
虽然我是在愚弄自己
Even though I do make a fool of myself.
但如果不是因为他… 我就不会认识你
But, you know, if it weren't for him, I never would have met you.
但…他就是你
But he is you.
- 真让人搞不清楚 - 对我而言并不会
- It's kind of confusing. - Not to me, it isn't.
一切都很清楚
Everything's clear.
直到昨天 我们一直遗忘 这座中部的
Until yesterday, a middle-American town that Middle America had forgotten.
中型美国市镇 现在人口已达123人
But today, the population…Exaggerated reports put it at 123.
因为增加了3个人
has increased by three.
这三名新来的人马上带来毁坏
And these three new arrivalsbring destruction in their wake.
今天早上我向东休士顿看去
As I look west into East Houston this morning…
- 这座小镇充满了恐惧 - 那是谁？
- …I see a town gripped with fear. - Who's the guy?
抓那个人 跟住他
Get that guy. Follow the guy.
那个大个子是谁？
Who's the big guy?
是的 我们遇上…
Okay, yeah, we've got a…
- 知道吗？ - 不知道
- You got that? - No.
- 没问题 - 试着前复摆动一下
- That's fine. - Try to wiggle it.
有哪些人能看到？
Who else is seeing this?
利用卫星连线 全世界所有人都能看到
Well, with this satellite linkup, just about everybody. The whole planet.
整个休士顿星吗？
The whole planet Houston?
是地球 整个地球
Earth. The whole planet Earth.
你可以继续转播
You may continue.
随着这桩意外事件的发展
As the extraordinary story continues…
- 随着这桩意外事件… - 这男人够了吧
- Enough of this man. - As this extraordinary…
如果全世界都在收看 能否让他们看些有趣画面？
If the whole planet is watching, let's show them something interesting.
把武器放下投降
Throw down your arms and surrender!
这是命令
This is an order.
查德将军不接受命令 他是下命令的人
General Zod does not take orders. He gives them.
他就在火线上 但是却毫发无损
He was in the line of that fire and nothing happened to him.
我没有看过这种事 除了超人之外
I haven't seen the likes of this since Superman.
是的
Yes? Yes.
控制室已经通知我 有一队 武装直升机已经上路了
The News beat control room has informed me that a fleet of helicopter gunships is…
- 总统先生 难道我们不能… - 恐怕没有人有办法
- Mr. President, sir, can't we… - There's nothing anybody can do.
他们拥有强大的力量 什么都阻档不了他们
They have such powers, nothing can stop them.
超人在哪里？
Where's Superman?
他在哪里？ 为什么他不想想办法？
Where is he?Why doesn't he do something?
再发射
Fire again.
你看 他们要利用机器才能飞
Look. They need machines to fly.
- 降落了 - 真是英勇啊
- Banking now. - What bravery.
对他们好一点 送他们个飞吻
Be nice to them, my dear.Blow them a kiss.
火箭准备就绪 瞄准目标中 等等…
Rockets ready. Coming in on target.Wait, wait.
我们要下坠了
We're out of control.
我们要坠机了
We're coming in, coming down.Can't control it!
We're coming down.
我赢了
I win.
我每次都会赢
I always win.
全地球没有人敢向我挑战吗？
Is there no one on this planet to even challenge me?
过来
Come forward.
将军阁下有话要说
Your general wishes to speak.
我是查德将军 你们的统治者
I am General Zod, your ruler.
是的 今天以新的命令开始
Yes, today begins a new order!
你们的土地 财产和生命
Your lands, your possessions…
全部都要献给我 查德将军
…your very lives will gladly be given in tribute to me.
为了回报你们的服从…
In return for your obedience…
你们将享有我慷慨的保护
…you will enjoy my generous protection.
换官之 我允许你们活下去
In other words, you will be allowed to live.
你是名将军…
So you are a general?
谁是你的上级长官？
And who is your superior?
- 我只对总统负责 - 而他将对我负责
- I answer only to the president. - And he will answer to me.
否则所有城市的下场 都将像这座小镇一样
Or all of his cities will end up like this one.
花了数千小时才创造完成 几秒钟之内就已模糊不清
Thousands of hours to create, and they defaced it in seconds.
如果我们反抗 想想看他们会怎么做
Imagine what they'll do to the world if we resist.
你的星球的人对你很满意 凯尔
The people of your planet are well-pleased with you, Kal-El.
你竭诚为他们服务 他们也很威激
You have served them faithfully, and they are grateful for it.
但你居然又回来与我理论
And yet you have returned to reason with me once again.
儿子 我一直尝试 预测你所有的问题 卡尔
My son, I have tried to anticipate your every question.
我连想都没…
This was one I'd…
我希望你不会问到这个问题
I'd hoped you would not ask.
我的情感…
My attachment…
我对某位人类发展出的情悻
…the feelings which I have developed for a certain human being…
已深深影响我 父亲
…have deeply affected me, Father.
你投注原本该给所有人的时间与情感
You cannot serve humanity by investing your time and emotion in one human being…
在一个人身上 便无法服务全人类
…at the expense of the rest.
- 这两件事互不相容 - 那么…
- The concepts are mutually exclusive. - And…
若我再也不愿为全人类服务
…if I no longer wishto serve humanity…
你要这样回报他们的感激吗？
Is this how you repay their gratitude?
丢下弱小的 无法自我保护的 有需要的人
By abandoning the weak, the defenseless, the needy…
只为了你自私的追求？
…for the sake of your selfish pursuits?
自私？在我为他们做了那么多之后？
Selfish? After all I've done for them?
我的服务 会有功德圆满的一天吗？
Will there ever come a time when I've served enough?
至少他们有幸福的机会
At least they get a chance for happiness.
我也只要幸福 不需要更多
I only ask as much, no more.
你的幸福层次更高
Yours is a higher happiness.
你一定有感觉到 完成使命的鼓舞
The fulfillment of your mission, an inspiration you must have felt.
你心里一定体会过那种幸福
You must have felt that happiness within you.
儿子 你无法否定那种感受
My son, surely you cannot deny that feeling.
不 我的确不能
No, I cannot…
但也无法否定另外这股 更强的威觉 父亲
…any more than I can deny the other, which is stronger in me, Father.
它强烈的多了
So much stronger.
真的没有办法吗 父亲？
Is there no way then, Father?
难道我将得不到 生命中唯一真正渴望之物？
Must I finally be denied the one thing in life which I truly desire?
若你不是凯尔…
If you will not be Kal-El…
若你是他们的一员…
…if you will live as one of them…
并如此爱他们的一员…
…love their kind as one of them…
你必须变成
…then it follows that you must…
一个普通人
…become one of them.
这座水晶舱中充满氪星的太阳光
This crystal chamber has in it the harnessed rays of the red sun of Krypton.
一旦受到这些光线曝晒
Once exposed to them…
你在地球上所有的力量
…all your great power son Earth will disappear.
都将永远消失
Forever.
因为一旦做了将无法回头
Once this is done, there's no going back.
你会感觉像个普通人
You will feel like an ordinary man.
也会像普通人一样受伤
And you can be harmed like an ordinary man.
三思啊 凯尔
Think, Kal-El.
我求求你
I beg you.
父亲…
Father…
我爱她
…I love her.
要三思 凯尔
Think, Kal-El.
快走…
Come on. Come on.
小心
Look out!
你就是他们称为总统的人？
You are the one they call president?
我就是
I am.
我认为你很崇敬飞行物
I see you are practiced in worshipping things that fly.
很好
Good.
在查德面前不能坐着
Rise before Zod.
现在到查德面前跪下
Now, kneel before Zod.
你不是总统
You are not the president.
一个统治那么多人的人 不会那么快就下跪
No one who leads so many could possibly kneel so quickly.
我是他们保护的对象
I am the man they are protecting.
我是总统
I am the president.
如果能救大家的命 我愿下跪
I'll kneel before you if it will save lives.
会的
It will.
从救你自己的命开始
Starting with your own.
这肯定是个落后的星球
What a backward planet this must be…
男人们穿戴缎带
…where the men wear the ribbons…
与珠宝
…and the jewelry.
我现在做的
What I do now…
都是为了全球人类
…I do for the sake of the people of the world.
但地球上还有一个人 绝不会向你下跪
But there is one man here on Earth who will never kneel before you.
那个笨蛋是谁？他在哪里？
Who is this imbecile? Where is he?
我希望我知道
I wish I knew.
天啊
Oh, God.
查德
Zod.
喂
Hey.
你真的很安静
You're awfully quiet over there.
是的 我正在想…
Yeah, I was just thinking…
我不相信你竟会为我放弃一切
…I can't believe what you've given up for me.
你在闲玩笑？那么做不仅为你 露易丝 我是为了我们而做
Are you kidding? I didn't do it for you, Lois, I did it for us.
我告诉过你附近有家热狗店
See, I told you there'd be a hot dog place somewhere.
好吧 因为你不能飞 所以得花多一点时间
Okay. It sure takes longer when you can't fly.
快一点
Hurry up.
- 快点 - 好的
- Come on. - Okay.
来吧 我请客
Come on, it's my treat. Come on.
天啊 是完美先生
Oh, boy, it's Mr. Wonderful.
哦？谢谢
Thank you.
- 请问有男厕所吗？ - 此在转角
- Do you have a men's room? - Yeah. Right in the corner.
- 想要坐下吗？ - 好的
- Want to sit down? - Yeah.
你们想吃点什么？
Hi, what would you folks like?
我要一套总汇起士汉堡 和一杯可乐…
I'd like a cheeseburger with everything on it, and a Coke…
还要一份薯条及一份沙拉
…an order of fries and a side salad, please.
- 你呢？先生 - 等我回来再点
- And for you, sir? - I'll think about it when I get back.
没问题 总汇起士汉堡
Right. That's one cheeseburger…
- 牛排加蛋 只煎单面 咖啡 - 我的可乐 谢谢
- Steak and eggs, over easy, coffee. - Can I have my Coke?
马上来
Coming right up.
- 对不起 这个位子有人坐 - 正是现在 亲爱的
- I'm sorry, that seat's taken. - It is now, sweetheart.
我能请你吃东西吗？
Can I buy you something to eat?
不用了 谢谢
No, thank you.
对不起 你坐了我的位置
Excuse me. I think you're sitting in my seat.
你的位置在那边 四眼田鸡
Your seat's in there, four-eyes.
或许该有人教教你礼貌 先生
Gee, I think perhaps somebody ought to teach you some manners, sir.
是吗？等他来了再告诉我
Yeah? Well, let me know when he comes in.
- 我们只是想… - 亲爱的…
- Look, Clark, we can just… - Honey.
对不起 先生 你愿意到外面去吗？
Excuse me, sir, would you care to step outside?
我说 请问先生 你愿意到外面去吗？
I said, excuse me, sir, would you care to step outside?
听我说 你的牛排马上好
Now, listen, Rocky, your steak's coming right up.
让它在炉上热着 这件事只需要一分钟就解决
Keep it on the flame, Ron.This is just a minute steak.
你先请
After you.
- 克拉克 - 没关系的 宝贝
- Clark. - It's all right, honey.
克拉克
Clark!
你还好吗？
You all right, fella?
他会没事的 把毛巾给我
He's gonna be fine, just give me that.
- 克拉克？ - 血 是我的血
- Clark?- Blood. It's my blood.
我想… 或许从现在起 你该雇个保镖
I think maybe we ought to hire a bodyguard from now on.
我不需要保镖 我要我爱上的那个人
I don't want a bodyguard.I want the man I fell in love with.
我知道 露易丝
I know that, Lois.
我希望他在这里
I wish he were here.
克拉克
Clark.
天啊 你还不打算罢手吗？
Boy, you just don't have enough sense to stay down, do you?
你…不是个好人
You… You… You are no good.
大家住手
Settle down!
反正我不喜欢你的肉
I don't like your meat anyway.
天啊
Oh, God.
克拉克？…
Clark? Clark?
你站得起来吗？
Clark, can you get up?
- 没事的 我来扶你 - 慢慢来
- All right. Come on. I got you. - Go slow. Go slow.
试着坐到椅子上
Try and get up in that chair.
- 坐下 - 我没事
- Sit down. - I'm all right. I'm all right.
他没事 大家放轻松 我们还有些新煮的咖啡
Okay, everybody, he's all right.Just relax. We'll have some fresh coffee.
我把电视打开
I'll turn the box on.
本台节目暂时中断 播报一则紧急消息
We interrupt this program for an urgent message…
由美国总统宣布
…from the President of the United States.
我是美国总统
This is your president.
我代表美国 和世上其他领袖之名
On behalf of my country, and in the name of the other leaders of the world…
以及今天我所咨询过的相关人员
…with whom I have today consulted…
我在此宣布放弃…
…I hereby abdicate…
我所有的权力 以及地球的控制权
…all authority and control over this planet…
让予查德将军
…to General Zod.
查德
Zod.
唯有完全听从 他的命令才能活命
Only by strict compliance with all his directions…
才得以拯救千百万无辜性命
…will the lives of innocent millions be spared.
超人 你听到了吗？
Superman, can you hear me?
- 超人 你到底在哪… - 谁是超人？
- Superman, where? - Who is this Superman?
你会知道的 到时候…
You'll find out. And when you do…
来找我 超人 如果你敢的话
Come to me, Superman, if you dare.
我向你中挑战
I defy you.
过来 到查德面前下跪
Come! Come and kneel before Zod.
查德
Zod!
- 这里？什么时候？ - 什么时候？
- Here? When? - When?
你上哪儿去了？ 废弃的荒岛吗？
Where the hell have you been, Mac? On a desert island?
我必须回去
I have to go back.
你不能回去
You can't go back.
- 现在已经没办法了 - 我必须去
- There's no way now. - I have to.
我一定要试试看 该死 我什么办法都要试
I've gotta try, damn it. I've gotta try something, anything.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你不知道会发生这种事
You didn't know this was gonna happen.
他知道
He knew.
我听到他说的
I heard him.
但我却不在意
I just didn't listen.
所有的调查都由你主导
You're master of all you survey.
我昨天也一样
And so I was yesterday.
还有前天也是
And the day before.
嗨 你们好
Hello, there.
我是雷克斯路瑟
Lex Luthor.
或许你们听过这个名字 我是地球上最伟大的罪犯
You've heard the name? The greatest criminal mind on Earth.
我告诉过你这只是个小星球
I told you this was a puny planet.
请等一下
Wait just a moment.
等你们更了解我再说好吗？
Wait until you get to know me better. Will you, please?
等等 你们想要什么 我都能提供
Wait. Look, I can give you anything you want.
我可以给你勇气 让你们有无限自由去残害…
I can give you the brass ring…
杀戮和毁灭
…the unlimited freedom to maim, kill, destroy.
加上雷克斯路瑟敏锐的心灵 雷克斯路瑟的见解
Plus, Lex Luthor's keen mind.Lex Luthor's savvy.
雷克斯路瑟是生涯导师 雷克斯路瑟是优质教师
Lex Luthor's career guidance.Lex Luthor's School of Better…
不用你 我们这些早就有了
We have all of this without you.
你不能用我们已有的东西协议
You cannot bargain with what you don't have.
至尊
Magnificent One…
我要用你没有的来协议
…what I am bargaining with is what you do not have.
乔尔的儿子
The son of Jor-El.
乔尔的儿子？
The son of Jor-El?
我是这么说的 对吧？
I said that, didn't I?
囚禁我们的乔尔？
Jor-El, our jailer?
不是 是棒球选手乔尔
No, Jor-El, the baseball player.
对啦 囚禁你们的乔尔
Yes, Jor-El, your jailer.
- 乔尔的儿子？他在地球？ - 对
- The son of Jor-El? On this planet? - Aye.
或许你们比较熟悉他的化名
Possibly you know him better by his nom de voyage…
或是他用旅行用的名字
…or his name he travels under:
超人
Superman.
原来是超人
So this is Superman.
你怎么认识乔尔？
How do you know of Jor-El?
我是全心全意的 正如我先前向你解释的…
My Fullness, as I explained to you before…
我是地球上最棒的
…I'm about the best there is.
复仇
Revenge.
我们将杀了狱卒的儿子
We will kill the son of our jailer.
- 复仇 - 复仇 我们正在进行
- Revenge. - Revenge! Now we're cooking.
- 他会飞吗？ - 经常飞
- He flies, then? - Constantly.
- 他的力量跟我们一样吗？ - 当然
- He has powers as we do? - Certainly.
但是… 至尊
But, Magnificent One…
他只有一个人
…he's just one…
而你们有三个
…where you are three.
- 如果你把他算两次 就有四个 - 我们会让他下跪
- Or four, if you count him twice. - We will bring him to his knees.
等一下
Wait!
你们得先找到他才行
First, you must find him.
唯有雷克斯宝贝知道他在哪里
And Lex Baby is the only one who knows where he is.
你… 想要什么？
What do you want?
将军…
Well, general…
这个是个广大的星球
…the world is a big place.
感谢上帝…
Thank goodness…
我的需求很小
…my needs are small.
海景的资产对我特别有吸引力
As it turns out, I have this affinity for beach front property.
你…想要什么？
What do you want?
我要澳洲
Australia.
嘿
Hey.
听着 拜托 你去…？ 请停下
Listen… Hey, come on, where are you… Please!
父亲？
Father?
若你听得到我的话
If you can hear me…
我失败了
…I failed.
我让你失望
I failed you…
我让自己失望
…I failed myself…
也让全人类失望
…and all humanity.
我用与生俱来的权利…
I've traded my birthright…
在由你的敌人统治的世界里 换取屈从的一生
…for a life of submission in a world that's now ruled by your enemies.
已经没有人能帮助…
There's nobody left to help them now…
这个世界的人们
…the people of the world.
至少在我…
Not since I…
父亲
Father!
好好听着 吾儿 这将是我们最后一次谈话
Listen carefully, my son, for we shall never speak again.
若你现在听得到我
If you hear me now…
那你便使用到仅剩的能力之一
…then you have made use of the only means left to you:
便是让我们开始沟通的水晶源头
The crystal source through which our communications begun.
这个过程已经完整
The circle is now complete.
凯尔 你犯了极大的罪过
You have made a dreadful mistake, Kal-El.
你以自由意志决定
You did this of your own free will…
枉我尽一切所能想说服你
…in spite of all I could say to dissuade you.
我…
I…
现在你回到我面前 最后一次试着证明自己
Now you have returned to me for one last chance to redeem yourself.
这部分最后我也预料到了 吾儿
This too finally I have anticipated, my son.
看着我 凯尔
Look at me, Kal-El.
当你小时候 我曾死过一次
Once before when you were small, I died…
是为了给你生命
…while giving you a chance for life.
现在 虽然这将用尽 我体内最后的能量…
And now, even though it will exhaust the final energy left within me…
父亲 不要
Father, no.
看着我 凯尔
Look at me, Kal-El.
氪星的预官终于将被实现
The Kryptonian prophecy will be at last fulfilled.
儿子变成父亲 父亲化为儿子
The son becomes the father, the father becomes the son.
永别了 凯尔
Farewell forever, Kal-El.
要记得我 吾儿
Remember me, my son.
吾儿
My son.
父亲
Father!
哈洛 黑咖啡 不加糖
Harold. Coffee, black, no sugar.
黑咖啡 不加…
Black, no sug… Yeah. Yeah.
谁付钱啊？
Who's paying, huh?
不 那里有三个人 有荒谬的将军
No, no! There's three of them.That cockamamie general…
一辆长头发的大卡车 和像伸展台皇后的女人
…and a big truck with hair on it and a broad that looks like the queen of the runway.
他们能飞 能透视 超人能做的 他们都办得到
They can fly, they can see through things.Anything Superman can do, they can do.
他人呢？
Where is he, anyway?
也许他还没有听到消息 老编
Maybe he hasn't heard about it yet, chief.
- 或许… - 或许他的胆量用完了
- Maybe… - Maybe he's just run out of guts.
- 不加糖 而且别叫我老编 - 他会来的
- No sugar. And don't call me "chief." - He'll be here.
- 如果他有办法他一定会来的 - 没错 他一定会来的
- If there's any way at all, he'll be here. - Yeah, he'll be here.
- 现在怎么样了？ - 我不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know.
- 你感觉到了吗 查理？ - 有
- Hey, Charlie, you feel that? - Yeah.
感觉好像地震
Sounds like an earthquake.
我的天啊
Oh, my!
- 正是那三个 - 停
- It's those three. - Stop!
- 天啊 他们已经来了 - 不好了
- Oh, my God, they're here now! - Oh, no!
好恐怖
This is scary!
你没事吧？老编
You all right, chief?
嗨
Hi.
你们该看看白宫 得好几个月才能清干净
You should see the White House.They'll be cleaning for months.
我是雷克斯路瑟
Lex Luthor.
你猜不到吧？
Wouldn't you know it?
这是乔尔的儿子？
This is the son of Jor-El?
- 不 但你一定是个… - 吉姆
- No, but I bet you're a son of a… - Jimmy!
你答应给我乔尔的儿子
You promised me the son of Jor-El.
没错 阁下
Yes, Your Grace.
但是… 我所给你的是次好的
But what I've given you is the next best thing.
抓住那位小姐… 他一定会来…
You just hold on to that little lady, and he'll be along.
他们有这种特殊关系
See, they have this relationship.
她替他做公共关系 而他给她所有独家新闻
She does all his public relations, and he gives her every exclusive.
他们是最好的朋友 了解我的意思吗？
They're the best of friends.You know what I mean?
这个超人还真随便
What an undemanding male this Superman must be.
你也需要改进一点
You could use a tuck here and there yourself, sister.
等一下
Wait!
- 对不起 - 她暂时可以活命
- I'm sorry! - She lives for now.
把其他人都杀了 就从他开始
Kill the rest, starting with him.
等等…
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
等一下 等一下
Wait. Wait.
还记得白宫吗？椭圆形办公室 我们曾有过欢笑
Don't you remember the White House?The Oval Room? We had a few laughs there.
你们一定要改一改
You ought to have that fixed.
（白宫投降）
将军
General…
没听过媒体言论自由吗？
…haven't you heard of freedom of the press?
- 超人 - 感谢老天 是超人
- Superman! - Superman, thank God.
我叫你去抓他
I mean, get him!
到我面前来 乔尔之子
Come to me, son of Jor-El!
到查德面前下跪
Kneel before Zod!
小心 你没事吧？
Watch out. You all right?
（白派瑞 总编辑）
乔尔之子
Son of Jor-El.
我们开始以为你是个懦夫
We were beginning to think you were a coward.
我不是懦夫 查德
I'm not a coward, Zod.
你八成只是个笨蛋
It is extremely likely you are merely a fool.
有其父必有其子
Like father, like son.
小心
Look out!
你该死就得死
Then die as you deserve to!
快 抓住他
Come on, come on, Superman! Get him!
一定会没事的
Man, this is gonna be good.
超人
Superman.
- 那是老编的 - 老编已经有了
- Hey, that's the chief's. - The chief's got it.
什么 你打了女人？
What, you hit a woman?
天啊 我的小孩
Oh, my God! My baby!
救救我的宝贝
Help my baby!
哦？谢谢
Thank you.
这个超人没什么了不起
This Superman is nothing of the kind.
- 我已经发现他的弱点了 - 是啊
- I've discovered his weakness. - Yes.
他关心
He cares.
他真的很关心地球人
He actually cares for these Earth people.
- 此像宠物一样？ - 我想是吧
- Like pets? - I suppose so.
我来分散他的注意力
I'll draw his fire…
用我自己的力量
…with some of my own.
那些车子怎么了？
What's happening to those cars?
别挡路
Get out of the way!
（冷静一下）
超人
Superman.
（请享用可口可乐）
真是谢谢你
Oh, thank you!
我没想到这事会持续这么久
I never thought this thing would go the distance.
不要 别动手
No! Don't do it!
车上的人
The people!
扔啊
Throw it!
- 别靠近那里 远离那个地方 - 我们快去帮他们
- Get away from there. Get away from there. - Let's help them out!
- 别担心 我去救她 - 他死了
- I got her. I got her. Don't worry. - He's dead.
超人死了
Superman is dead.
他们杀了超人
They've killed Superman.
- 他死了 - 我们去找他们报仇
- He's dead. - Let's go get them!
- 来 让他们知道我们的厉害 - 我会空手道 上啊
- Come on, we'll show them! - I know some judo. Let's go!
来吧
Come on!
我抓住了 我抓住了
I'm holding it, I'm holding it!
什么都看不到能做什么？
What can you do if you can't see what's happening?
- 抓稳了 - 天啊
- Hold on! - Oh, my God!
（不准进入）
（准备下地狱吧 世界末日到了！）
你不能丢下我们
You can't leave us!
那么 他毕竟是个懦夫
So he is a coward after all.
他走了
He's gone.
回来 超人
Come back, Superman!
别丢下我们
Don't leave us!
他临阵逃脱了
He chickened out.
骗子
Phony!
超人 什么都没做
Superman didn't even do nothing.
我们走
Come on, let's go.
- 他们在那儿 - 快走开 吉姆
- There they are. - Get away from here. Jimmy.
我们已经战胜了
Our victory is complete.
乔尔之子逃跑了
The son of Jor-El has fled.
- 超人跑掉了？ - 我不相信你
- Superman fled? - I don't believe you.
你听到了 三对一 你大获全胜
You heard him. Three against one, you should've taken two ears and a tail.
- 他被我们吓走了 - 他会回来的
- He fled in fear of us. - He'll be back.
只要他还活着 就会再试一次
As long as he's alive, he's gonna try again.
- 下一次 我们会杀了他 - 下一次？
- The next time, we will kill him. - The next time?
下一次？
The next time?
我该拿你们怎么办？
What am I gonna do with you people?
我在这里等着超人出现
I held up my end.I delivered you the blue boy.
你们三位要如何回报我？
What do I get from my triple threat?
「鞠躬 屈膝 下跪」 这种事在这里不管用
"Bow, yield, kneel."That kind of stuff closes out a town.
你为什么这样对我说话？ 你明知我可以因此而杀你
Why do you say this to me when you know I will kill you for it?
杀我？雷克斯路瑟？
Kill me? Lex Luthor?
杀掉本世代最伟大的罪犯
Extinguish the greatest criminal flame of our age?
- 杀掉地球上唯一… - 杀了他
- Eradicate the only man on earth with… - Let me kill him!
超人的地址？
Superman's address?
你还要什么？ 我看到你脸上写满贪婪
What more do you want?I can see the greed written on your face.
一个小奖励 最棒的
A small incentive, O Fullest One.
一样挑起回忆的小东西
A mere bauble to jog the memory.
还要什么？
What more?
古巴
Cuba.
雷克斯路瑟 希望你不是在浪费我的时间
I trust you are not wasting my time, Lex Luthor.
当然不是 难搞的大人
Of course not, Your Turbulence.
现身吧 懦夫
Show yourself, coward!
懦夫的儿子
Son of a coward!
我在这里 查德
I'm here, Zod.
- 放莲恩小姐走 我们到里面谈谈 - 不要 超人
- Let Miss Lane go, step inside. We'll talk. - No, don't, Superman!
别听他的 他只是个…
Please don't listen to him. He's just…
停手
Stop.
你的能力与我的相同
Your powers are identical to mine.
但我们有三个人 可以把你五马分尸
But we are three.We could tear you limb from limb.
下手吧 将军大人
Do it, Your Grace.
抱只腿 许个愿
Just grab a leg and just make a wish.
但你是另一项致命弱点的受害者
But you are victim to another fatal weakness…
就是你的同情心
…your compassion.
对你来说 他人的死比你自己的更重要
The death of others means more to you than your own.
是的 但偶有例外
Yes, with rare exceptions.
你父亲让我们进人间炼狱永不得翻身 你的命运也将相同
Your father condemned us to an eternal living death. Your fate will be the same.
凯尔 你将永远活着
You will live, Kal-El, forever…
做我的奴隶 否则他人将为你的固执付出代价
…as my slave. If not, then other swill pay for your obstinate attitude.
无辜的人 必要时可达上百万 就从这位露易丝开始
Innocent people, millions if necessary, beginning with this Lois person.
- 超人 不要 - 停手
- Don't, Superman, don't! - Stop it!
好吧 查德
All right, Zod.
一切都结束了
It's over.
将军大人 别相信他 你不像我如此了解他
Your Grace, don't believe him!You don't know him the way that I do.
我感觉到乔尔在这里
I sense the presence of Jor-El here.
我们会毁了这个地方
We will destroy this place.
然复杀了他
And then kill him.
他
Him.
是他还是我？
Him? Me?
将军大人 我是雷克斯路瑟
General, this is Lex Luthor.
记得吗？在你失意时我帮过你
Remember? I helped you through the tough times.
我让你充满力量
I filled your inside straight.
当初你双手空空来找我 而我给了你超人
You came to me with nothing.I gave you Superman.
安静
Silence!
听好…
Well, look…
这家伙真的很笨
Guy's a clod.
你还以为了解人们 是吧？
You think you know people, right?
协议已经达成 也交换了礼物
Promises were made, gifts were exchanged.
我必须信任你 你说的都是实话
I gotta hand it to you, you know.You always told the truth.
你很清楚谁跟你是同一阵线
A guy always knew where he stood with you.
试着把他们骗进这个分子室
Try to get them all into this molecule chamber here.
它会夺走他们的力量
It takes away their powers, see…
使他们成为平凡的人类
…and turns them into ordinary human beings.
如果你能够…
Now, if you could…
- 不要进去 那是个陷阱 - 你这个狡猾的家伙
- Don't go in there. It's a trap. - Luthor, you poisonous snake!
那是个分子室
That's a molecule chamber.
它会把你们变成跟我一样
It makes people like you into people like me.
- 你做的很好 雷克斯路瑟 - 我也这么觉得
- You've done well, Lex Luthor. - I thought so.
抓住他
Seize him.
- 杀了她 - 不要 超人
- Kill her. - No! Superman, no!
好啦 查德 别伤害她
All right! All right, leave her alone, Zod!
你赢了
You win.
那颗水晶能够启动机器
General, the crystal there activates the mechanism.
雷克斯路瑟 澳洲统治者
Lex Luthor, ruler of Australia…
去启动机器
…activate the machine.
请你允许
With your permission.
现在终于…
And now, finally…
跪下
Kneel.
握着我的手…
Take my hand…
发誓永远效忠查德
…and swear eternal loyalty to Zod.
他转换了机器
He switched it.
他将他们变弱了
He did it to them.
我是说光线在外面 而他在里面很安全
The lights were on out here while he was safe in there.
你知道吗？
Hey, you know something?
你真的是个讨厌鬼
You're a real pain in the neck!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我知道你会反叛我 狡猾的你忍不住会说谎
I knew you'd double-cross me, Luthor.A lying weasel like you couldn't resist.
你在开玩笑吗？
Who, me? Are you kidding?
我一直是跟你同阵线 真的好美
Hey, I was with you all the time. That was beautiful.
你看到他们掉入陷阱的样子？
Did you see the way they fell into our trap?
太迟了 太迟了
Too late, Luthor. Too late.
你看 是超人
Look. Look, Superman.
我有个建议
I got a proposition for you.
不要阻止我 直到你听说这个…
Now, don't stop me till you've heard this…
我知道我还欠你一次 但我们还在北极 对吧？
…because I know I owe you one, but we're in the North Pole, right?
听着 露易丝…
Look, Lois…
我不后悔 好吗？ 我做到了
No regrets, okay? I did it.
我让我爱的男人爱我
I got the man I loved to love me.
- 对不对？ - 没错
- Didn't I? - Oh, yeah.
好 此这样 那些人需要你
Well, okay then. Those people need you.
你以为我不懂吗？
Do you think I don't understand that?
你知道的 我们依然可以见面 常常见面
We can still see each other, you know.I mean, all the time.
但就是不能…
But it just can't be…
只要别忘记就好了
Just don't forget, that's all.
永远别忘记
Don't ever forget.
- 我们到了 - 甜蜜的家
- Well, here we are. - Home sweet home.
- 早上在办公室见 - 朝气蓬勃 是吧？
- See you at work in the morning. - Bright and early, huh?
- 原来的克拉克与原来的露易丝 - 没错
- The same old Clark and the same old Lois. - Yup.
不过… 或许以后我会对你好一点
Except… maybe I won't be quite so mean to you from now on.
你不用担心
You don't have to worry.
我会保守你的秘密
Your secrets safe with me.
我知道 露易丝
I know. I know that, Lois.
他走了 孩子
Well, there he goes, kid.
在天空飞翔
Up, up and away.
（号外 超人拯救人类 免于永恒统治）
（畅饮 可口可乐）
- 不要 - 不要
- No! - No!
- 白先生有空吗？ - 他正在讲电话
- Hey, is Mr. White free? - On the telephone.
- 他现在正在开会 - 对 这是他的说辞
- He's in conference at the moment. - Yeah, that's what he says.
（星球日报）
好 给我三份副本
All right, give me three carbons of that.
- 你好 - 这将是报纸中的夹页
- Hi. - It's gonna be an insert in the paper.
他们是这么说的
That's what they said.
早安 你好
Good morning. Hi.
早安 露易丝
Good morning, Lois.
- 早安 露易丝 - 你好 克拉克
- Good morning, Lois. - Hi, Clark.
天啊 我看过不少人做白日梦
Jeepers, I have seen some faraway looks in my time…
但你这副德行 大概已飘到北极去了
…but with that look, you might as wellbe on the North Pole.
北极
The North Pole.
不 那太傻了
No, that's too silly.
你是否曾经觉得 你知道很重要的事 你得…
Did you ever feel like you knew something that was so important that…
不 你从来没有过
No, you never did.
我是说 我觉得手上有 整个生涯最重要的新闻
I mean, I feel like I'm sitting on the singlemost important story of my career…
却记不得那是什么
…and I can't remember what it is.
以我对你的了解 那一定跟超人有关
Well, knowing you, it must have been about Superman.
也许是他如何拯救这座城市 拯救地球 或拯救宇宙
Maybe how he saved the city or saved the world or saved the universe.
克拉克… 听我说 忌妒会让生产力下降
Clark, Clark. Listen.Jealousy's really counter productive.
你也可以做点别的事
Now, there's some things that you can do too.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
真的吗？做什么？
Really? Like what?
帮我们叫彼萨
Get us a pizza.
- 现在要叫彼萨？ - 对 我饿了
- A pizza. Now? - Yeah, I'm hungry.
说真的 我想白先生要是发现 不会太高兴…
Actually, I don't think Mr. White would like it if…
我出一半钱 好吗？
I'll pay for half of it, all right?
我去
I'm going.
露易丝？
Lois?
你知道 彼萨的事？
You know, about the pizza?
没关系 我请客
It's okay. I'll pay for the whole thing.
你知道吗 你人最好了
You know, you're really super.
（超人今日休息）
- 你好 朗 - 什么事？
- Hey, Ron. - Yeah?
再给我一盘这种垃圾
Give me another plate of this garbage.
垃圾？这是最受欢迎的特餐
Garbage? That's my number-one special, Rocky.
好 再多给我一些咖啡好吗？
All right. Get me some more coffee too, will you?
哇 真有趣 我没看过垃圾在吃垃圾
Gee, that's funny. I've neverseen garbage eat garbage before.
对不起 先生 你坐了我最爱的位子
Excuse me, sir. I think you're sitting in my favorite seat.
有本事过来抢 四眼田鸡
Come and get it, four-eyes.
冷静点 洛奇
Now cool it, Rocky.
别激动
Take it easy, will you?
这里我才刚修好 我可是花了一大笔钱
I just had this joint fixed.It cost me a fortune.
天啊
Oh, God!
外带
This order's to go.
（攻击吧）
对于你的损失我成到很抱歉
I'm terribly sorry about all the damage, sir.
我一直在练健身
I've been working out.
自70年代此片拍摄以来 人们已有更高度的认知
不论是对皮草业 对动物造成的摧残
还是吸烟与二手烟 造成的健康危害
因此我将不宽恕 如本片描述般的
消费香烟与皮草